# **MASSIMINO Pascal**

Compression - Image & Media processing - Large-Scale Engineering

C++, assembly (NEON, x86), GLSL, and anything around to make these work and shipped. See github repos. Deep hands-on 'get things done' engineering, along with a researcher mindset. Hardware and software.

pascal.massimino@gmail.com cell: +33 6 51 92 05 90 - Paris Area - https://skal65535.github.jo

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Google** — Principal Engineer

2006 - PRESENT:

- <u>Streetview</u>: imagery, backend, serving, <u>ipeg compression</u> (used everywhere at Google)
- YouTube: back-end, video compression, thumbnails, processing pipeline, Video for VR
- WebP: initiator of the format, wrote most of the initial code, worked with the ecosystem on adoption and user support.
  - Public talks to influencers: <u>2020 WebP Rewind</u>, <u>2021 WebP Recap</u>
  - WebP2: Next-gen format my team and I experimented with.
  - Researched <u>compressing images</u> in ~200 bytes (<u>paper</u>)
- AOMedia: developing AV1/AVIF with industry partners.
  - Public advocate and speakers: #1 in french, #2, #3, slides, ...
- Manager of small dedicated team
- 21 US patents

### **XviD Solutions GmbH** — Co-Founder

2000 - 2007, Video Codec Consulting & Development

Co-Founded <u>Xvid Solutions</u> to leverage the open-source development of the <u>XviD</u> code (in <u>Ffmpeg</u> notably).

Wrote MPEG2, H263, H264 codecs for various DSP platforms in all sorts of low-level languages.

Shipped in volume to numerous set-top boxes and home devices.

## **Ilog**, Paris — Senior Engineer

2000-2005, Operation Research and Constraint Propagation technology.

Worked on the flagship **Scheduler** product until the acquisition by IBM.

### **EDUCATION and RESEARCH**

# PhD, 1999 — Theoretical Physics

- Elastic Ising Models : Modèle d'Ising compressible (in french)
- Effect of magnetoelastic interactions on the phase transition of two-dimensional Ising spin system

Alma mater: Ecole Normale Superieure de Paris (1991)

#### **SIDE INTERESTS**

- FinTech: business angel and investor, notably for Kard
- Entrepreneur / consulting: metaskal.com
- Marathon & Trail runner Rock Climbing Muay Thai Music & Rock band